Inventory of the Austin-Twyman Papers, 1765-1939
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Accounts and Legal Papers, 1765-1919, n.d. (Folder 167-404)
  - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1774-1928, n.d. (Folder 326-371)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1811., 44 items. (Folder 338)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1812., 34 items. (Folder 339)
      Includes document dated "Cold Comfort 5 February 1812" and signed by Mary and Martha Harrison, sisters of Benjamin Harrison dealing with his slave estate.
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1813., 93 items. (Folder 340)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1814., 14 items. (Folder 341)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1815., 28 items. (Folder 342)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1816., 17 items. (Folder 343)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1817., 21 items. (Folder 344)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1818., 15 items. (Folder 345)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1819., 19 items. (Folder 346)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1820., 21 items. (Folder 347)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1821., 16 items. (Folder 348)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1822., 33 items. (Folder 349)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1823., 40 items. (Folder 350)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1824., 24 items. (Folder 351)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1825., 17 items. (Folder 352)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1826., 12 items. (Folder 353)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1827., 11 items. (Folder 354)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1828-1829., 11 items. (Folder 355)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1830-1832., 32 items. (Folder 356)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1833-1835., 30 items. (Folder 357)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1836-1839., 30 items. (Folder 358)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1840-1843., 42 items. (Folder 359)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1844-1846., 99 items. (Folder 360)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1847-1849., 52 items. (Folder 361)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1850-1855., 57 items. (Folder 362)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1856-1859., 23 items. (Folder 363)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1860-1862., 22 items. (Folder 364)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1863-1869., 27 items. (Folder 365)
      Includes extract of Special Order #64 of May 29, 1865 concerning "harsh or cruel treatment" of employees.
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1870-1889., 38 items. (Folder 366)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, 1890-1928., 23 items. (Folder 367)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts and Legal Papers, n.d., 217 items. (Folder 368-371.)
  - County Accounts and Legal Papers, 1765-1919. (Folder 372-403)
    - Buckingham County Records, 1800-1919, n.d. (Folder 372-398)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1765-1799., 16 items. (Folder 372)
        Includes land grant of 1789 signed by Governor Beverly Randolph.
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1800-1801., 21 items. (Folder 373)
        Includes "A list of Magistrates as also those named in different Commissions of the Peace for Buckingham County" for 1777-1800.
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1802., 24 items. (Folder 374)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1803., 8 items. (Folder 375)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1804., 16 items. (Folder 376)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1805., 18 items. (Folder 377)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, January-February 1806., 14 items. (Folder 378)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, March-April 1806., 21 items. (Folder 379)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, May-June 1806., 46 items. (Folder 380)
        Includes judgment involving Randolph Jefferson and John Jefferson.
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, July-August 1806., 33 items. (Folder 381)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, September-October 1806., 7 items. (Folder 382)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, November-December 1806., 27 items. (Folder 383)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1807., 35 items. (Folder 384)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1808., 23 items. (Folder 385)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1809., 29 items. (Folder 386)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1810., 35 items. (Folder 387)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1811-1812., 28 items. (Folder 388)
        Includes "A list of a Company of Light Infantry --- of the 100th Regiment (of) Buckingham Militia," 19 April 1812.
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1813-1814., 18 items. (Folder 389)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1815-1819., 18 items. (Folder 390)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1820-1824., 33 items. (Folder 391)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1825-1829., 23 items. (Folder 392)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1830-1839., 14 items. (Folder 393)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1840-1849., 173 items. (Folder 394-395)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1850-1869., 16 items. (Folder 396)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, 1870-1919., 6 items. (Folder 397)
      - Accounts and Legal Papers of Buckingham County Records, n.d., 23 items. (Folder 398)
    - Albermale and Amherst County Records, 1789-1861., 77 items. (Folder 399)
    - Appomattox County Records, Botetourt County Records. Campbell County Records, 1804-1874., 16 items. (Folder 400)
    - Cumberland County Records, 1774-1848., 29 items. (Folder 401)
    - Goochland County Records, King and Queen County Records, Nelson County Records, 1774-1855., 21 items. (Folder 402)
    - Powhatan County Records, Prince Edward County Records, 1800-1810., 20 items. (Folder 403)
  - Accounts and Legal Papers - Scraps, n.d., 57 items. (Folder 404)
- Poetry and religion manuscripts, n.d., 37 items. (Folder 405)
- Recipes and formulae manuscripts, n.d., 27 items. (Folder 406)
- Memoranda manuscripts. n.d., 201 items. Entire box. (Folder 407)
- Photographs, n.d., 7 items. Photographs. (Folder 408)
  Series 4: Genealogical Material
- Genealogical Material, n.d. (Folder 409-422.)
  - Austin Family, n.d., 5 items. (Folder 409)
    Genealogical Materials.
  - Booker Family, n.d., 7 items. (Folder 410)
  - Byrd Family, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 411)
  - Clark Family, n.d., 2 items. (Folder 412)
    Genealogical Materials. See also Rogers and Twyman.
  - Gainer Family, n.d., 15 items. (Folder 413)
  - Lewis Family, n.d., 34 items. (Folder 414)
    Genealogical Materials. See also Rogers.
  - Montague Family, n.d., 2 items. (Folder 415)
  - Rogers Family, n.d., 16 items. (Folder 416)
  - Spiller Family, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 416A)
    Genealogical Materials. See also J. M. Spiller Ledger (cash accounts). 1839-57, pp. 80-81 and pp. 292-294 for family notes by Spiller.
  - Twyman Family, n.d., 135 items. (Folder 417-420)
  - Walker Family, n.d., 5 items. (Folder 421)
  - Miscellaneous Names - Greenwood, Gwathmey, etc., n.d., 10 items. (Folder 422)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter, n.d., 116 items. Entire box. (Folder 423)
  Series 5: Manuscript Volumes
- Manuscript Volumes, 1799-1896, n.d. (Volume MsV. 1-53)
  This series is divided into subseries by family name first and all other items not associated with a particular name are located at the end of the series.
  - Adams Family, 1799-1801. (Volume MsV. 1)
    Account book of William Adams and his estate.
  - Austin Family, 1804-1848, n.d. (Volume MsV. 2-5)
    - Accounts of Archibald Austin (1772-1847), 1804-1832. (Volume MsV. 2)
    - Attorney fee book of Archibald Austin (1772-1837), 1807-1835. (Volume MsV. 3)
    - Accounts of Archibald (1772-1837), 1824-1848. (Volume MsV. 4)
      Accounts of Archibald, 1824-1828. Court records, 1847-1848.
    - Twyman and Austin notebook of miscellany, n.d. (Volume MsV. 5)
  - Twyman Family, 1832-1879. (Volume MsV. 6-18)
    - Accounts of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1832-1837. (Volume MsV. 6)
    - Accounts of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1840-1843. (Volume MsV. 7)
    - Accounts of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1844. (Volume MsV. 8)
      Includes James River and Kanawha Canal accounts.
    - Accounts Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1845. (Volume MsV. 9)
    - Account book of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1846. (Volume MsV. 10)
    - Account book of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1847. (Volume MsV. 11)
    - Account book of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1848. (Volume MsV. 12)
    - Account book of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1849-1864. (Volume MsV. 13)
      Account books, 1849-1856, including farm notes, 1860-1864.
    - Dr. Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman farm and household accounts, 1853-1867. (Volume MsV. 14)
    - Accounts of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1854-1856. (Volume MsV. 15)
      Including farm notes and notes of calls on patients.
    - Account book of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, 1856-1863. (Volume MsV. 16)
    - Notes of calls by Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, January - March 1860. (Volume MsV. 17)
    - School notes of Dr. and Mrs. Iverson L. Twyman, Jr., 1877-1879. (Volume MsV. 18)
  - Spiller Family, 1829-1892. (Volume MsV. 19-47)
    - Account book of J. M. Spiller, 1829-1838. (Volume MsV. 19)
      Includes farm notes in back, 1840.
    - Ledger of J. M. Spiller, 1829-1847. (Volume MsV. 20)
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller ?, 1850-1868. (Volume MsV. 21)
      Including the estate of George Spiller.
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, Mayo's Island, 1836-1838. (Volume MsV. 22)
      Includes time charts for worker in the James River and Kanawha Canal.
    - Ledger of J. M. Spiller and Thomas A. Mera, 1837-1839. (Volume MsV. 23)
    - Ledger and Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1839-1892. (Volume MsV. 24)
      Ledger of J. M. Spiller, 1839-1859, other accounts 1886-1892. Spiller genealogical data, pp. 80-81, 292-294.
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1846-1865. (Volume MsV. 25)
      Including time sheets of work on locks, James River and Kanawha Canal.
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1850-1851. (Volume MsV. 26)
      Includes work on the James River and Kanawha Canal.
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1851-1867. (Volume MsV. 27)
    - Cash book of J. M. Spiller, 1852-1853. (Volume MsV. 28)
      Includes vouchers of Ada and Sarah Bocock.
    - Account book of J. M. Spiller, 1852-1865. (Volume MsV. 29)
    - Cash book of J. M. Spiller, 1854-June 1855 (Volume MsV. 30)
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1854-1869. (Volume MsV. 31)
    - Cash book of J. M. Spiller ?, 1855-1856?. (Volume MsV. 32)
    - Cash book of J. M. Spiller, 1856. (Volume MsV. 33)
    - Cash book of J. M. Spiller, 1856-1863. (Volume MsV. 34)
    - Cash book of J. M. Spiller, 1857-1858. (Volume MsV. 35)
    - Account book of J. M. Spiller, 1862-1867. (Volume MsV. 36)
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1867-1873. (Volume MsV. 37)
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, Castle Mills, 1867-1878. (Volume MsV. 38)
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1869-1873. (Volume MsV. 39)
    - Religious notes and clippings of Emma C. Spiller, 1875-1894. (Volume MsV. 40)
    - Flour grinding accounts of J. M. Spiller, Castle Mills, 1871-1875. (Volume MsV. 41)
    - Account book of J. M. Spiller, Castle Mills, 1875-1879. (Volume MsV. 42)
    - Ledger of J. M. Spiller, 1876-1882. (Volume MsV. 43)
    - Account book of J. M. Spiller, Castle Mills, 1880-1886. (Volume MsV. 44)
    - Farm notes of J. M. Spiller ?, 1881. (Volume MsV. 45)
    - Ledger of J. M. Spiller, 1882-1888. (Volume MsV. 46)
    - Accounts of J. M. Spiller, 1882. (Volume MsV. 47)
  - Buckingham Court House decisions involving debts, 1845-1847. (Volume MsV. 48)
  - Unidentified accounts, 1850. (Volume MsV. 49)
  - Unidentified accounts and school attendance records, 1860. (Volume MsV. 50)
  - Unidentified, including travel notes and total abstinence pledge, 1844. (Volume MsV. 51)
  - Unidentified, including farm account, 1892-1896. (Volume MsV. 52)
  - Index to Account Book, n.d. (Volume MsV. 53)